<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title> on Lets Learn Hugo </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://codein-dwij.github.io/blog_hugo/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 19:20:14 IST</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fossasia - Codein Organiser</title>
      <link>http://codein-dwij.github.io/blog_hugo/post/fossasia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 19:20:14 IST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://codein-dwij.github.io/blog_hugo/post/fossasia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google Code-in 2015 has 14 organisations out of which one of them is &lt;a href =&#34;http://fossasia.org/&#34;&gt;Fossasia.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fossasia puts many tasks which include the task &amp;ldquo;Setup a Blog Using Hugo&amp;rdquo;. The mentors are really good and help the students everytime they are stuck.
There tasks include use of Github and git.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FOSSASIA is the premier Free and Open Source technology organization in Asia for developers, designers, start-ups, and contributors. Projects at FOSSASIA range from open hardware, to design, graphics and software. FOSSASIA was established in 2009. The annual FOSSASIA took place in Cambodia, Vietnam and Singapore. FOSSASIA meetup groups exist throughout Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There tasks include use of programming languages like python,css and javascript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with FOSSASIA proved helpful for me and I learnt a new thing which I had never heard before like hugo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pushing Your Blog to Github And Viewing as Github pages</title>
      <link>http://codein-dwij.github.io/blog_hugo/post/github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 17:48:41 IST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://codein-dwij.github.io/blog_hugo/post/github/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IMP :- This post is based on the windows version of hugo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may visit &lt;a href =&#34;http://codein-dwij.github.io/blog_hugo/post/learn/&#34;&gt;Link &lt;/a&gt; For the repository&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Our last post, we had done making the blog. Now we will be pushing it to Github. To do this you must have a little knowledge about using Git and Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First Create a new repository on your account.Once done open your cmd and set your location to a folder named public where your blog was created . Now type the following commands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;                                            git init

                                            git checkout --orphan gh-pages                                              

                                            git add .

                                            git commit -m &amp;quot;Initial Commit&amp;quot;

                                            git remote add origin [YOUR_REPOSITORY_LINK]     { For Example :- git remote add origin https://github.com/codein-dwij/blog_hugo.git }

                                            git push origin gh-pages
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now enter your account details and press enter. Your blog is successfully pushed to Github. To View Your blog , type on the address bar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;                                            http://YOUR_USERNAME.github.io/REPOSITORY_NAME   { For Example :- http://codein-dwij.github.io/blog_hugo}                                           
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may see your blog generated there. You can add more posts to your blog , generate it using &amp;ldquo;hugo &amp;ndash;&amp;rdquo; command and push it to github!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lets Learn To Setup a Blog Using Hugo</title>
      <link>http://codein-dwij.github.io/blog_hugo/post/learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 18:52:35 IST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://codein-dwij.github.io/blog_hugo/post/learn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IMP - This post is based on WINDOWS version of Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo is a static website generator. Okay, our first step is to have Hugo and Git installed on your PC. Once installed, make sure it is kept in your system path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run cmd on you PC and set the location where you want to work on the blog.After doing that that type the following command :-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;                             hugo new site [Folder name you want to create]    {for example :- hugo new site learn}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new folder will be created where you set the location. Now type another command to add a new post to your blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;                             hugo new post/[post name].md                      {for example :- hugo new post/first.md}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we need to add a theme for our blog..  create a folder named themes and change the location of your cmd to themes folder and type the next command&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;                             git clone [the theme repository link]             {for example :- git clone https://github.com/SenjinDarashiva/hugo-uno.git}                                
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once it has been cloned, go to the folder where we made our blog. You may see a file called config.toml. Edit it using notepad or any text editor. You may see a code &amp;ldquo;title=&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;. you may edit the title to any title you want.
Then add a new line of code :-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;                             theme = &amp;quot;[theme name]&amp;quot;                            {for example :- theme = &amp;quot;hugo-uno&amp;quot;}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After doing this, return back to the folder and you will find a folder called content and then post. Your post will be there. Edit it now. You may write whatever you want to below the &amp;ldquo;+&amp;rdquo; sign as it is the content of your post.Save your file after doing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final step is to type the following command :-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;                             hugo server -w
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open your browser and type the following and press enter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;                             http://localhost:1313
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, Lets build our blog. For that type :-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;                            hugo --
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all , Our Blog is ready. You may later upload it to github and use it as a page..&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
